hey folks David Tao with barbin.com and
today we've got some of our favorite
moments from the 2023 Noble CrossFit
Games it was a big year there were new
Champions on the men's side the women's
side and the teams division not to
mention lots of action from the age
group and adaptive divisions it was uh
a tumultuous year it was a surprise year
there were crashes there were burnouts
there were gutsy performances and even
some inspiring moments we've got our
favorite so stick around but before we
get into that make sure to subscribe to
Bar bend on YouTube because we've got
the latest and greatest from
weightlifting powerlifting CrossFit
strongman bodybuilding and more along
with equipment reviews supplement
reviews everything you need to know to
get stronger and fitter today so go
ahead and subscribe all right the first
memorable moment we want to highlight
from this year's CrossFit Games well we
say memorable maybe surprising is the
word and that's a rough start for
two-time defending champion and fitness
man on Earth Justin Maderos who began
the games with his worst ever games
finish on any event he finished 29th in
the bike race it was a lot of twists and
turns it was a long race and Maderos
crashed not once but twice we could see
visible abrasions on his chest for
basically the rest of the competition
and it clearly set his games off on the
wrong foot he finished and is still
extremely respectable 13th Place overall
but it wasn't really what we were
expecting out of the gates for a man who
many thought was poised to three-peat so
that's our first surprising moment and
it was really a disappointing moment for
many fans but we know Justin Medeiros
will be back fighting and fitter than
ever next year our our second memorable
moment for the 2023 CrossFit Games comes
from 21 year old athlete Jack Farlow now
we've seen in the past younger athletes
in the men's and women's divisions tend
to struggle or fall behind or lag behind
a little bit when it comes to max
strength output and those really heavy
lifts that's because well they just
haven't had enough time to build that
strength but clearly not a problem for
Jack Farlow who clean and jerked
396 pounds a CrossFit Games record for
individuals in the Olympic weightlifting
event for the individuals 396 pounds and
he made it look pretty darn clean so 21
year old Jack Farlow one of the younger
competitors in the field clearly the
strongest Olympic Lifter on the men's
side this year our third moment it was a
tough one to watch but it led to some
inspiring moments later on in the games
and that came from Roman krenikov
krenikov is a games athlete who has been
on the cusp of potentially being the
fittest on Earth for some years he was a
Podium finisher last year and this year
he was actually wearing the white leader
Jersey for a portion of the games
unfortunately during event 10 krenikov
landed awkwardly the event was called
muscle up logs and seemed to break his
foot or at the very least tear some
important ligaments in his foot we're
still waiting on the final diagnosis he
was wearing the white leader Jersey for
a portion of the weekend and even with a
foot that he couldn't really put any
weight on he still finished on the
podium this year but it knocked him out
of first place and it leads to the
question what would have happened if he
hadn't been injured would Roman
krennikoff be standing on the top of the
podium it led to some gutsy performances
in events 11 and 12 including Roman
actually doing heavy rope double unders
on one foot now there was no minimum
work requirement for that next event but
he said he wanted to go out there and
give it his all and Inspire his young
son who was watching from the stands so
kritikov wow gutsy performance and that
really changed the tide of this year's
games that's not to say Jeffrey Adler of
Canada who ended up coming in first
place overall all wouldn't have won had
Roman not been injured we just don't
know but for someone in the leader
position to suffer a significant injury
like that and Start Tumbling Down the
leaderboard well it was unprecedented
and we're happy Roman was able to hang
on and still finish in third place
overall that's how good his performance
was through the first 10 events on the
weekend our fourth memorable moment and
there are so many memorable moments
comes from multi-time CrossFit Games
veteran Danielle Brandon who absolutely
scorched the inverted medley event she
been finish this relatively short event
a full 34 seconds faster than the next
closest competitor Brandon has always
excelled at gymnastics movements but she
clearly Was A Cut Above this year and
even eclipsed past performances she's
had upside down it was an impressive
performance really a clinic in all of
these movements and it led to the
question is it humanly possible to go
faster than she did on that medley
probably not by much our fifth memorable
moment from the 2023 CrossFit Games
comes from Young Canadian athlete Emma
Lawson who at 18 years old is the
youngest athlete to ever stand on the
CrossFit Games individual Podium now
Lawson really burst into the public view
last year where at 17 years old she
finished in sixth place overall on her
way to rookie of the year but the
Canadian she outdid herself this year
she was actually in the leader position
for much of the weekend ended in a
silver medal position right behind Laura
Horvath of Hungary and Emma Lawson 18
years old of Canada is the youngest ever
Podium finisher at the CrossFit games
not bad for someone who just turned 18.
so there you have it those are just some
of our favorite moments from this year's
CrossFit games there are so many more
and we recap a lot of inspiring
performances as well as all of the
results from the men's women's teams
adaptive and age group divisions on
barbend.com we'll link those below you
can also Google bar band plus 2023
CrossFit games for all of that I wish we
had more time to go into some specifics
for example there were some Masters
athletes who racked up their fourth
fifth even six CrossFit Games titles
there were plenty of inspiring
performances in the Adaptive and age
group division we want to know which
events or which performances would you
put at the top of your list for most
inspiring from this year's CrossFit
games let us know in the comments below
we'll try and respond to every one of
them until then I'm David Tao thanks for
tuning in
oh